Let me show you why we achieved a really, really important step.
非常に重要なステップに到達したわけをお見せしましょう
First, I rewrite the second term over here in this way,
始めに この 2 番目の項を次のように書きなおします
where I split x_1 to t minus one,
まず x_t-1
to z_t minus one,
Z_t-1 および
and z_1 to t minus two.
Z_1 t-2 に分解します
If you compare this with our formula from the very beginning over here,
この式を最初のここにある式と比較すると
you can see that this term here is
この項は 先に出てきた
exactly the belief from the previous timestep, t minus one.
信念 (bel) の 時刻 t を t-1 としたものと同じです
Now, we can rewrite the integral with a belief x_t minus one inside.
ここで 積分を信念 x_t-1 として書き換えることができます
The amazing thing is,
驚くべきことに
that we have a recursive update formula.
これで再帰的更新式を得ることができました
You use to estimate its state from
この式を使い 前の時刻 (t-1) の値から
the previous timestep for the prediction of the current one.
現在の値 (t) の予測値を計算します
This is one of the most important steps as a recursive Bayesian filter
観測全体と制御履歴から独立しているため
because we are independent from the whole observation and control history.
これは再帰的ベイズフィルターとして重要なステップの1つとなっています
So, in the graph structure,
このグラフ構造で
I replace this part over here with the belief x_t minus one.
この部分を 信念 x_t-1 に置き換えます
Finally, you can replace the integral by a sum over all
最後に このケースでは離散ローカライゼーションのシナリオがあるため
x_i's because you have a discrete localization scenario in this case.
積分をすべての x_i の合計に置き換えます
By the way, you already saw this formula in Sebastian's lesson for localization.
ところで あなたはセバスチャンのローカライゼーションの講義中でこの式を既に目にしています
The process of predicting x_t with the previous beliefs,
前の信念 xt-1 から xt を推定するプロセスと
x_t minus one, and the transition model is technically a convolution.
遷移モデルは 実質的には畳み込み処理となっています
Now, you also know the full mathematical background and how to derive this module.
ではここで 詳しい数学的裏付けとこのモデルの導き方を確認しましょう
If you take a look to the formula again,
公式を再度確認すれば
it is essential that the belief at x_t
時刻 x_t での信念 ＝ 0 が有意な仮定で
equals zero is initialized with meaningful assumption.
初期化されていることが重要だとわかります
It depends on the localization scenario how you set the belief,
信念の設定方法 言い換えればどのようにフィルターを初期化するかは
or in other words, how you initialize your filter.
ローカライゼーションシナリオによって左右されます
For example, you can use GPS to get a course estimate where you are.
たとえば ロケーションをのコース予測であれば GPS を使用できます
So, let's sum up to this point.
では まとめてみましょう
You learned again, how to apply the law of
全確率の公式に新しい変数 x_t-1 を適用する方法について
total probability by including the new variable, x_t minus one.
再度学習しました
You also learned about the Markov Assumption,
また 確率的推論において重要な
which is very important for probabilistic reasoning.
マルコフ仮定についても学習しました
And finally, you learned how to derive the recursive filter structure.
そして最後に 再帰的なフィルター構造の導出方法を学習しました
Next, you will implement a motion model in C++.
次のコンセプトでは C++ でモーションモデルを実装します
You will also learn how to initialize our localizer,
また ローカライザーの初期化方法 つまり
which means, defining the belief of the state at the very beginning.
初期状態の信念の定義方法についても学習します
So, let's do it.
では やってみましょう